<TEI xmlns="http://www.tei-c.org/ns/1.0">
   <teiHeader>
      <fileDesc>
         <titleStmt>
            <title>Proclamation anent the deficients of the levies 1693 and 1695</title>
            <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
         </titleStmt>
         <editionStmt>
            <edition>
               <date>1697</date>
            </edition>
         </editionStmt>
         <extent>Approx. 7 KB of XML-encoded text transcribed from 1 1-bit group-IV TIFF page image.</extent>
         <publicationStmt>
            <publisher>Text Creation Partnership,</publisher>
            <pubPlace>Ann Arbor, MI ; Oxford (UK) :</pubPlace>
            <date when="2011-04">2011-04 (EEBO-TCP Phase 2).</date>
            <idno type="DLPS">B05513</idno>
            <idno type="STC">Wing S1659</idno>
            <idno type="STC">ESTC R183382</idno>
            <idno type="EEBO-CITATION">53299267</idno>
            <idno type="OCLC">ocm 53299267</idno>
            <idno type="VID">180001</idno>
            <availability>
               <p>To the extent possible under law, the Text Creation Partnership has waived all copyright and related or neighboring rights to this keyboarded and encoded edition of the work described above, according to the terms of the CC0 1.0 Public Domain Dedication (http://creativecommons.org/publicdomain/zero/1.0/). This waiver does not extend to any page images or other supplementary files associated with this work, which may be protected by copyright or other license restrictions. Please go to https://www.textcreationpartnership.org/ for more information about the project.</p>
            </availability>
         </publicationStmt>
         <seriesStmt>
            <title>Early English books online.</title>
         </seriesStmt>
         <notesStmt>
            <note>(EEBO-TCP ; phase 2, no. B05513)</note>
            <note>Transcribed from: (Early English Books Online ; image set 180001)</note>
            <note>Images scanned from microfilm: (Early English Books, 1641-1700 ; 2810:26)</note>
         </notesStmt>
         <sourceDesc>
            <biblFull>
               <titleStmt>
                  <title>Proclamation anent the deficients of the levies 1693 and 1695</title>
                  <author>Scotland. Privy Council.</author>
                  <author>Scotland. Sovereign (1694-1702 : William II).</author>
               </titleStmt>
               <extent>1 sheet ([1] p.)   </extent>
               <publicationStmt>
                  <publisher>Printed by the heirs and successors of Andrew Anderson ...,</publisher>
                  <pubPlace>Edinburgh, :</pubPlace>
                  <date>1697.</date>
               </publicationStmt>
               <notesStmt>
                  <note>Caption title.</note>
                  <note>Title vignette: royal seal.</note>
                  <note>Intentional blank spaces in text.</note>
                  <note>Imperfect: cropped at top with some loss.</note>
                  <note>Reproduction of original in: National Library of Scotland.</note>
               </notesStmt>
            </biblFull>
         </sourceDesc>
      </fileDesc>
      <encodingDesc>
         <projectDesc>
            <p>Created by converting TCP files to TEI P5 using tcp2tei.xsl,
      TEI @ Oxford.
      </p>
         </projectDesc>
         <editorialDecl>
            <p>EEBO-TCP is a partnership between the Universities of Michigan and Oxford and the publisher ProQuest to create accurately transcribed and encoded texts based on the image sets published by ProQuest via their Early English Books Online (EEBO) database (http://eebo.chadwyck.com). The general aim of EEBO-TCP is to encode one copy (usually the first edition) of every monographic English-language title published between 1473 and 1700 available in EEBO.</p>
            <p>EEBO-TCP aimed to produce large quantities of textual data within the usual project restraints of time and funding, and therefore chose to create diplomatic transcriptions (as opposed to critical editions) with light-touch, mainly structural encoding based on the Text Encoding Initiative (http://www.tei-c.org).</p>
            <p>The EEBO-TCP project was divided into two phases. The 25,368 texts created during Phase 1 of the project (2000-2009), initially available only to institutions that contributed to their creation, were released into the public domain on 1 January 2015. The approximately 40,000 texts produced during Phase 2 (2009- ), of which 34,963 had been released as of 2020, originally similarly restricted, were similarly freed from all restrictions on 1 August 2020. As of that date anyone is free to take and use these texts for any purpose (modify them, annotate them, distribute them, etc.). But we do respectfully request that due credit and attribution be given to their original source.</p>
            <p>Users should be aware of the process of creating the TCP texts, and therefore of any assumptions that can be made about the data.</p>
            <p>Text selection was based on the New Cambridge Bibliography of English Literature (NCBEL). If an author (or for an anonymous work, the title) appears in NCBEL, then their works are eligible for inclusion. Selection was intended to range over a wide variety of subject areas, to reflect the true nature of the print record of the period. In general, first editions of a works in English were prioritized, although there are a number of works in other languages, notably Latin and Welsh, included and sometimes a second or later edition of a work was chosen if there was a compelling reason to do so.</p>
            <p>Image sets were sent to external keying companies for transcription and basic encoding. Quality assurance was then carried out by editorial teams in Oxford and Michigan. 5% (or 5 pages, whichever is the greater) of each text was proofread for accuracy and those which did not meet QA standards were returned to the keyers to be redone. After proofreading, the encoding was enhanced and/or corrected and characters marked as illegible were corrected where possible up to a limit of 100 instances per text. Any remaining illegibles were encoded as &lt;gap&gt;s. Understanding these processes should make clear that, while the overall quality of TCP data is very good, some errors will remain and some readable characters will be marked as illegible. Users should bear in mind that in all likelihood such instances will never have been looked at by a TCP editor.</p>
            <p>The texts were encoded and linked to page images in accordance with level 4 of the TEI in Libraries guidelines.</p>
            <p>Copies of the texts have been issued variously as SGML (TCP schema; ASCII text with mnemonic sdata character entities); displayable XML (TCP schema; characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or text strings within braces); or lossless XML (TEI P5, characters represented either as UTF-8 Unicode or TEI g elements).</p>
            <p>Keying and markup guidelines are available at the <ref target="http://www.textcreationpartnership.org/docs/.">Text Creation Partnership web site</ref>.</p>
         </editorialDecl>
         <listPrefixDef>
            <prefixDef ident="tcp"
                       matchPattern="([0-9\-]+):([0-9IVX]+)"
                       replacementPattern="http://eebo.chadwyck.com/downloadtiff?vid=$1&amp;page=$2"/>
            <prefixDef ident="char"
                       matchPattern="(.+)"
                       replacementPattern="https://raw.githubusercontent.com/textcreationpartnership/Texts/master/tcpchars.xml#$1"/>
         </listPrefixDef>
      </encodingDesc>
      <profileDesc>
         <langUsage>
            <language ident="eng">eng</language>
         </langUsage>
         <textClass>
            <keywords scheme="http://authorities.loc.gov/">
               <term>Taxation --  Law and legislation --  Scotland --  Early works to 1800.</term>
               <term>Broadsides --  Scotland --  17th century.</term>
            </keywords>
         </textClass>
      </profileDesc>
      <revisionDesc>
         <change>
            <date>2008-10</date>
            <label>TCP</label>Assigned for keying and markup</change>
         <change>
            <date>2008-12</date>
            <label>SPi Global</label>Keyed and coded from ProQuest page images</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Sampled and proofread</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-03</date>
            <label>Mona Logarbo</label>Text and markup reviewed and edited</change>
         <change>
            <date>2009-09</date>
            <label>pfs</label>Batch review (QC) and XML conversion</change>
      </revisionDesc>
   </teiHeader>
   <text xml:lang="eng">
      <body>
         <div type="royal_proclamation">
            <pb facs="tcp:180001:1" rendition="simple:additions"/>
            <!-- PDF PAGE 14 -->
            <head>
               <figure>
                  <p>DIEV ET MON DROIT</p>
                  <p>
                     <gap reason="illegible" extent="6 words">
                        <desc>〈◊◊◊◊◊◊〉</desc>
                     </gap>
                  </p>
                  <figDesc>royal blazon or coat of arms</figDesc>
               </figure>
            </head>
            <head>PROCLAMATION<lb/> Anent the Deficients of the Levies 1693 and 1695.</head>
            <opener>
               <signed>
                  <hi>
                     <seg rend="decorInit">W</seg>ILLIAM</hi> by the Grace of GOD, King of <hi>Great-Britain, France</hi> and <hi>Ireland,</hi> Defender of the Faith:</signed>
               <salute>To  <gap reason="blank" extent="1 span">
                     <desc>〈1 span left blank〉</desc>
                  </gap>  Macers of Our privy Council, Meſſengers at Arms, Our Sheriffs in that part, conjunctly and ſeverally, ſpecially conſtitute, Greeting:</salute>
            </opener>
            <p>Foraſmuch as by the Seventh Act of the Fourth Seſſion of Our current Parliament, there was an Offer made to Us of Two Thouſand Nine Hundred Seventy Nine Foot, to be Levied off the ſeveral Burghs and Shires of the Kingdom, effeirand to the proportions and number ſet down in the foreſaid Act; like<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>as, by the Thirty Third Act of the Fifth Seſſion of the ſame Parliament, It is Statute and Ordained, that there ſhould be Furniſhed to Us the Number of One Thouſand Men yearly, when we ſhould require them, and that in manner mentioned in the ſaid Act, of which two Levies for the ſaid year One Thouſand Six Hundred and Ninety Three, as alſo the ſaid year One Thouſand Six Hundred and Ninety Five, there are notwithſtanding of the ſeveral Proclamations emitted by Us in proſecution of the ſaid Acts a conſiderable Number of deficient Men yet reſting Unfurniſhed; and it being requiſite and neceſſary at this time, that the ſaids Deficients ſhould be put furth and furniſhed by the Heretors, and others lyable, to put furth the ſame with all Expedition: Therefore, We with Advice of the Lords of Our privy Council, have thought fit to Ordain, and do hereby peremptorly Require and Ordain the Commiſſioners of Supply of the ſeveral Shires, Stewartries and Burghs within this Kingdom, to meet at their reſpective Head-Burghs; theſe on this ſide of <hi>Tay,</hi> upon the Eleventh Day of <hi>March</hi> next to come; and theſe on the other ſide, and all the reſt of the Kingdom, upon the Twenty Third Day of the ſaid Month of <hi>March;</hi> with Certification to ſuch of them as ſhall not meet, that they ſhall be lyable each of them to the Penalties contained in the Acts of Parliament made anent the Militia: And they being Met, that they Conſider and Inquire diligently, how the Orders formerly given by them for the Outreick of the ſaid Levies have been obſerved; And for that Effect, they require the Heretors, Leaders of the foreſaid firſt Levy One thouſand Six hundred Ninety three: As alſo the particular Commiſſioners or Heretors Appointed for the Outreik of the ſaid Levy One thouſand Six hundred Ninety five, as they ſhall ſee Cauſe; either to produce a ſufficient Diſcharge or Document, that they have put Furth and Outreiked the Men, One or more falling to their ſhare, or at leaſt that they have Obſerved the Order of Lotting, Appointed by the foreſaid Act of Parliament One thouſand Six hundred Ninety five, with an Account of the Names and Deſignations of the Perſons one or more upon whom the Lots fell; and whether theſe perſons were Delivered, or given up as Deſerters, or otherwiſe; that the ſaids reſpective Heretors, Leaders and particular Commiſſioners, who cannot give a ſufficient Account for their Diſcharge in the Premiſſes, that they yet Exhibite and Produce the Men to the ſaids Commiſſioners, wherein they are Deficient, And that within the Number of Sixdays, after the days of Meeting hereby Appointed, to the ſaids Commiſſioners of Supply <hi>reſpective,</hi> who are hereby Ordained to deliver them to Collonel <hi>George Hamilton</hi> or his Order: Certifying, Likeas We hereby Certify and Decern ſuch Heretors, Leaders, or particular Commiſſioners Appointed for the foreſaids Levies, that ſhall failȝie in the Premiſſes, to pay each of them, One hun<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>dred Pounds <hi>Scots</hi> to the Officers Impowered for to receive the ſaid Deficients: which hundred Pounds <hi>Scots</hi> of Penaltie, is to be Decern<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ed for by any of the ſaids Commiſſioners of Supply at the Inſtance of the ſaids reſpective Officers: And the ſaid Commiſſioner of Supply, is hereby Impowered to give Precepts for Poynding for the ſame; And Poynding is hereby Appointed to follow thereon, ſicklike, in all Reſpects as is Ordained by the ſecond Act of the Parliament One thouſand Six hundred Sixty nine, Entituled <hi>Act concerning the Mili<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>tia:</hi> with this Alteration only, that the ſaid Commiſſioner Director of the Precept, may appoint Sheriff in that part, any whom the fore<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>ſaid Officer concerned, ſhall nominat: Providing nevertheleſs, that the perſon found lyable to the ſaid Fyne of: One hundred Pounds Penalty, ſhall have his Relief upon the perſons Lyable for the ſaids Levies, within his Allocation and Diſtrict, conform to the ſaid Act and Proclamations as Accords. And becauſe the effectual Diſpatch of this Affair, doth much concern Our Service; Therefore, We with Advice foreſaid, do peremptorly Ordain the foreſaid Commiſſioners of Supply, to return exact Accounts of their Diligence in the Premiſſes to the Clerks of Our Privy Council, within the ſpace of Twenty days after the ſaids reſpective Meetings, to the Effect, that all ſuch Commiſſioners as either ſhall not Meet, or ſhall not make due Returns of their ſaid Diligence, may be proceeded againſt by the Lords of Our Privy Council, conform to the Certification above-ſpecified, with all Rigor. <hi>Our Will is herefore,</hi> And We Charge you ſtrictly, and Command, that Incontinent theſe Our Letters ſeen, ye paſs to the Mercat-Croſs of <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> and to the Mercat-Croſſes of the re<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>manent Head-Burghs of the ſeveral Shires and Stewartries within this Kingdom; And there in Our Name and Authority, by open Pro<g ref="char:EOLhyphen"/>clamation make Intimation hereof, that none pretend Ignorance; and Ordains theſe Preſents to be Printed.</p>
            <closer>
               <dateline>Given under Our Signet at <hi>Edinburgh</hi>
                  <date>the Twenty Sixth Day of <hi>February,</hi> And of Our Reign the Eighth Year 1697.</date>
               </dateline>
               <signed>Per Actum Dominorum Secreti Concilii.
<hi>GILB. ELIOT,</hi> Cls. Sti. Concilii.</signed>
               <lb/>
God ſave the King.</closer>
         </div>
      </body>
      <back>
         <div type="colophon">
            <p>
               <hi>Edinburgh,</hi> Printed by the Heirs and Succeſſors of <hi>Andrew Anderſon,</hi> Printer to the Kings moſt Excellent Majeſty, 1697.</p>
         </div>
      </back>
   </text>
</TEI>
